# Thabani Tembe

## Software Developer

**PERSONAL:** 

**Gender:** Male **Home Language**: IsiZulu

Other Languages: English

**CONTACT:** 

Cell: 0765679248

Email:

thabanitembe@hotmail.com

GitHub:

https://github.com/Baintastic

#### **SUMMARY:**

A highly passionate full stack software developer with experience in developing web applications. Project management methodologies used include Agile and Scrum. I try to conform to good coding practices such as the use of KISS, DRY, SOLID principles which are of great importance when it comes to writing clean code.

I constantly work on improving my development expertise. I read on the latest technologies in my field of work and get to apply what I've learnt through side projects. I enjoy taking on new challenges and it's when I'm out of my comfort zone that I get exposure to new, different techniques and tools.

#### **EXPERIENCE:**

SA Home Loans, La Lucia, Kwa-Zulu Natal

March 2019 - Present

**Junior Software Developer** 

Development of an existing ASP.NET MVC web application which is a client portal that allows clients to view their home loan account, remaining term and also request money from their account. Automated the processing and disbursement of requested funds. Responsibilities included front-end design and development, writing unit tests using NUnit and liaising with clients on changes to existing software. Other duties included maintenance and improvement of the existing code base, code reviews, software architecture, database design/optimization, and bug fixing. Good coding practices were enforced and an Agile environment contributed to the product's success.

## March 2018 – February 2019

#### **IT Graduate**

Developed and maintained in-house solutions using C# code, ASP.NET and SQL depending on client requirements.

### **EDUCATION:**

University of Kwa-Zulu Natal, Durban, Kwa-Zulu Natal (2015 - 2017)

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science and Information Technology

Brettonwood High School, Durban, Kwa-Zulu Natal (2010 - 2014)

**SKILLS:** C# 2 ½ Years .Net 2 ½ Years SQL 2 ½ Years Git 2 ½ Years **HTML** 2 Years **CSS** 2 Years Docker 1 Year Angular 1 Year JavaScript 1 Year Typescript 1 Year **6 Months** Firebase

References available on request